<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adelie Developer&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>/projects/adg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/adg/</guid>
      <description>Beer me, Slackbot! 🍺 The Adelie Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group is an online, Slack-based study group for web development.
The group is beginner-friendly and project-oriented. Currently, some of the members are working on individual developer portfolio websites using modern front-end tooling and best practices.
Group Information &amp;amp; Resources    Group Resources Project Resources     Introduction To The Group Adelie YouTube Channel   Request Invitation Roster    We use Slack, HackMD, Github, CodePen, YouTube, and other collaborative tools to communicate, share design inspiration, tips, coding help and feedback, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milton Bros</title>
      <link>/projects/milton-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/milton-bros/</guid>
      <description>Milton &amp;amp; Candle The &amp;ldquo;Milton Bros&amp;rdquo; project was my first soiree into the world of character design. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had ambitions to develop a game - I think it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate form of expression - and while I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat comfortable in learning the development side of things, creating game art was always an extremely foreign world.
I designed Milton (pictured) and &amp;ldquo;Candle&amp;rdquo;, among several other bizarre characters, as a way to dive right into experimenting with simple shapes to build memorable characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosu</title>
      <link>/projects/mosu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mosu/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn, Hired, Vettery, Indeed, Monster&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;🙅 Mosu arose out of my personal frustration with the process of job hunting. There are something like a dozen different &amp;ldquo;job board&amp;rdquo; websites, each with their own quirks. I found myself running around between ten different accounts, trying to remember which job applications were in which &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;:
 Saved, or &amp;ldquo;To Be Applied To&amp;rdquo; Application sent Currently interviewing Successfully received an offer  The experience was complete 💩 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Messenger</title>
      <link>/projects/nightmessenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nightmessenger/</guid>
      <description>Ow, my eyes 👀 Messenger.com is a relatively little-known messaging interface for Facebook Messenger. It&amp;rsquo;s a great (and less power-hungry) alternative to the little chat window you get as part of the standard Facebook desktop experience.
I&amp;rsquo;d often work late in the night, and found that using Messenger.com would hurt my eyes. I had somewhat recently discovered the world of Chrome extension development, so I decided to dive in and see if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a darker theme for Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>