<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adelie Developer&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>/projects/adg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/adg/</guid>
      <description>🚨 A Note  Since the community first formed, many of ADG&amp;rsquo;s members have since gone onto gainful full-time employment and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the bitter-sweet realization that the group was no longer needed - not in its current form, to its current roster of members. While this isn&amp;rsquo;t quite &amp;ldquo;software&amp;rdquo; and I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to see the group evolve into something else, the chat group that was is due for a proper sunsetting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backlog CLI</title>
      <link>/projects/blg-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/blg-cli/</guid>
      <description>Backlog CLI An (unofficial) command line utility for working with Backlog, a tool by Nulab, Inc.
 View on Github  Values  Be easy to &amp;ldquo;plug and play.&amp;rdquo; Provide shortcuts for a subset of your most frequently repeated actions, rather than achieving complete feature parity. In other words, it is designed to be a complement to Backlog, rather than a replacement for it.  Main Features  Quickly create, view, and open pull requests in the browser for your current branch &amp;amp; issue  blg pr create [-b BRANCH_TO_MERGE_TO] blg pr ls blg pr open   View and open your latest notifications  blg n   Quickly access misc links  blg me to list links related to your user account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milton Bros</title>
      <link>/projects/milton-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/milton-bros/</guid>
      <description>Milton &amp;amp; Candle The &amp;ldquo;Milton Bros&amp;rdquo; project was my first soiree into the world of character design. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had ambitions to develop a game - I think it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate form of expression - and while I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat comfortable in learning the development side of things, creating game art was always an extremely foreign world.
I designed Milton (pictured) and &amp;ldquo;Candle&amp;rdquo;, among several other bizarre characters, as a way to dive right into experimenting with simple shapes to build memorable characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosu</title>
      <link>/projects/mosu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mosu/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn, Hired, Vettery, Indeed, Monster&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;🙅‍♀️ Mosu (NOW RETIRED) arose out of my personal frustration with the process of job hunting. There are something like a dozen different &amp;ldquo;job board&amp;rdquo; websites, each with their own quirks. I found myself running around between ten different accounts, trying to remember which job applications were in which &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;:
 Saved, or &amp;ldquo;To Be Applied To&amp;rdquo; Application sent Currently interviewing Successfully received an offer  The experience was complete 💩 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Messenger</title>
      <link>/projects/nightmessenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nightmessenger/</guid>
      <description>Ow, my eyes 👀 Messenger.com is a relatively little-known messaging interface for Facebook Messenger. It&amp;rsquo;s a great (and less power-hungry) alternative to the little chat window you get as part of the standard Facebook desktop experience.
I&amp;rsquo;d often work late in the night, and found that using Messenger.com would hurt my eyes. I had somewhat recently discovered the world of Chrome extension development, so I decided to dive in and see if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a darker theme for Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
