<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Oh | Web Developer on </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kevin Oh | Web Developer on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 16:33:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>windfall</title>
      <link>/posts/windfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 16:33:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/windfall/</guid>
      <description>🚨 [DRAFT 1.0]
Summary Windfall is a planned software project. It is engine that scrapes and parses news and social media sources and uses the gleaned data - in conjunction with machine learning - to predict stock market prices in real-time.
Windfall is composed of a series of modules. Below is a list of them and their intended function.
Getting Started Scraping Module, or scraper This module is responsible for the scraping of various news sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT BOARD</title>
      <link>/posts/project-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 21:47:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project-ideas/</guid>
      <description>This list is updated regularly. This is a list of project ideas that are either planned or in progress (but not complete enough to warrant inclusion on the main projects page).
   Name Description Technologies Status     Windfall A web scraper that parses a variety of social networks and does sentiment analysis to make predictions about stock performance, and then uses actual stock performance data to learn which sources are the best for making predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>string parsing &amp; data extraction</title>
      <link>/posts/developer-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 18:04:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/developer-site/</guid>
      <description>Summary My latest project at Nulab was to migrate over the old Developer Website (containing API documentation, mostly) from Drupal to something new. The old site had become somewhat clumsy to manage, and we needed a new solution.
After initially considering WordPress, we ultimately landed on Hugo, a static site generator (SSG) written in Go. An SSG was perfect for our use-case. But migrating the data was non-trivial. But first things first&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling 101: Package Managers</title>
      <link>/posts/package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 18:42:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/package-managers/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 of an introductory series on web development tooling. If you&amp;rsquo;re not a developer, this post will be ludicrously boring to you. 
Zoom back to 2012. I&amp;rsquo;m in my dorm room trying to learn Ruby on Rails. Everything is going smoothly! Rails seems magical - perhaps a bit too much. I try to add a feature or two, and my progress comes to a screeching halt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling 101: Introduction</title>
      <link>/posts/tooling-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 21:36:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tooling-101/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 of an introductory series on web development tooling. If you&amp;rsquo;re not a developer, this post will be ludicrously boring to you. 
While the barriers to web development are substantially lower than many other fields, there&amp;rsquo;s still a bunch of junk that makes it frustrating for beginners to jump in.
By &amp;ldquo;obstacles,&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t mean the inherent difficulty in learning a new field, nor the complexity of advanced web development topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adelie Developer&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>/projects/adg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/adg/</guid>
      <description>Beer me, Slackbot! 🍺 The Adelie Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group is an online, Slack-based study group for web development.
The group is beginner-friendly and project-oriented. Currently, some of the members are working on individual developer portfolio websites using modern front-end tooling and best practices.
Group Information &amp;amp; Resources    Group Resources Project Resources     Introduction To The Group Adelie YouTube Channel   Request Invitation Roster    We use Slack, HackMD, Github, CodePen, YouTube, and other collaborative tools to communicate, share design inspiration, tips, coding help and feedback, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Is Not That Hard</title>
      <link>/posts/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/coding/</guid>
      <description>Within the past two years, about a dozen people told me they’re extremely interested in learning how to code. Today, none of them are programmers, developers, or even hobby coders. Most of them, as far as I know, have never even opened a text editor.
The conversation always goes the same way. They want to learn, they have ideas, but it’s all too hard. One of my more determined friends — an art major — admired the idea of focusing on a single project all day, but he would routinely shudder at the sight of actual code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Design Is Not Subjective.</title>
      <link>/posts/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/design/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects.
There are times when the difference between two choices is completely lateral — two substitutable alternatives that are equal in importance and consequence. If you’re craving some fruit, it doesn’t matter whether you choose the apple or the orange. In these instances, it’s okay to defer to preference, precedent, or a coin toss. But these cases are the (rare) exception, not the rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milton Bros</title>
      <link>/projects/milton-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/milton-bros/</guid>
      <description>Milton &amp;amp; Candle The &amp;ldquo;Milton Bros&amp;rdquo; project was my first soiree into the world of character design. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had ambitions to develop a game - I think it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate form of expression - and while I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat comfortable in learning the development side of things, creating game art was always an extremely foreign world.
I designed Milton (pictured) and &amp;ldquo;Candle&amp;rdquo;, among several other bizarre characters, as a way to dive right into experimenting with simple shapes to build memorable characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosu</title>
      <link>/projects/mosu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mosu/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn, Hired, Vettery, Indeed, Monster&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;🙅 Mosu arose out of my personal frustration with the process of job hunting. There are something like a dozen different &amp;ldquo;job board&amp;rdquo; websites, each with their own quirks. I found myself running around between ten different accounts, trying to remember which job applications were in which &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;:
 Saved, or &amp;ldquo;To Be Applied To&amp;rdquo; Application sent Currently interviewing Successfully received an offer  The experience was complete 💩 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Messenger</title>
      <link>/projects/nightmessenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nightmessenger/</guid>
      <description>Ow, my eyes 👀 Messenger.com is a relatively little-known messaging interface for Facebook Messenger. It&amp;rsquo;s a great (and less power-hungry) alternative to the little chat window you get as part of the standard Facebook desktop experience.
I&amp;rsquo;d often work late in the night, and found that using Messenger.com would hurt my eyes. I had somewhat recently discovered the world of Chrome extension development, so I decided to dive in and see if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a darker theme for Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Day 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/techday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/techday/</guid>
      <description>Today, I got the awesome opportunity to represent one of Nulab&amp;rsquo;s apps, Typetalk.
I donned my Nulab tee and hoodie, strapped on the goldenrod &amp;ldquo;Tech Day Exhibitor&amp;rdquo; bracelet, and walked into the sprawling space. At first, I saw the big names - AWS, American Airlines, Vimeo. I continued to the rear end of the space, where we had a table. Japanese candies, t-shirts &amp;amp; totes, business cards, iPads, Macbook Pros with our apps on full-screen - we&amp;rsquo;re ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Blindly Loving Your Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tools/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects.
I once heard two friends arguing. One of them had recently come upon a windfall of cash, and wanted to make a big purchase: an upscale sports car. Upon hearing this, his miserly friend fired back, “you don’t even go places! Don’t buy a Porsche to drive to 711.”
When I heard this biting exchange, I chuckled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websites Are Like Pants</title>
      <link>/posts/websites-are-pants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/websites-are-pants/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects.
In 2005, psychologist Barry Schwartz took the stage at TEDGlobal in Oxford and proposed an idea: that “more is less.” You can watch the full video here, but the core idea is simple. To quote Schwartz, “With so many options to choose from, people find it very difficult to choose at all.” He tells a simple anecdote to that effect: many years ago, when he walked into a clothing store, there were only a few pairs of jeans to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>