<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Oh | Web Developer on </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kevin Oh | Web Developer on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 17:00:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automation with iOS Shortcuts, Raspberry Pi, NextJS, and Puppeteer</title>
      <link>/posts/ios-shortcuts-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 17:00:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ios-shortcuts-automation/</guid>
      <description>Yo, iOS Shortcuts is pretty cool I never really got into Automator, the long-lived macOS scripting utility. I assumed Shortcuts would be similar to Automator - lots of theoretical potential, but nothing that yielded a net value in that equation of Time Spent Automating vs Time Saved From The Automation. Not for my use-cases anyway.
But Shortcuts has a unique benefit over Automator. You can trigger scripts with Hey Siri! Easily, I mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toddlers in Porsches with Plasma Weapons</title>
      <link>/posts/toddlers-in-porsches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 17:00:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/toddlers-in-porsches/</guid>
      <description>Toddlers in Porsches with Plasma Weapons In this one TED talk, Malcolm Gladwell told a story about how the U.S. military once spent $3 billion dollars developing a &amp;ldquo;scope&amp;rdquo; (as in, a telescopic sight for a weapon) for planes to attack their targets with terrifying accuracy. When it worked, it was considered revolutionary. The so-called Norden Bombsight made it possible to &amp;ldquo;drop bombs into a pickle barrel from 20,000 feet.&amp;rdquo; God-like accuracy for the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Workflow Tips</title>
      <link>/posts/workflow-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:28:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/workflow-tips/</guid>
      <description>Tips &amp;amp; Tricks for Developer Efficiency (Indefinitely a WIP) This is a tl;dr of legitimate tricks that I wish I knew years ago.
For context, I work with VS Code on Mac.
macOS Tips  Use BetterTouchTool. I have three trackpad gestures I use a million times a day:  3-finger swipe up: Maximizes current window (not fullscreen) 3-finger swipe left: Moves window to left half of screen 3-finger swipe right: Moves window to right half of screen   CMD+``` switches between windows of the same app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling 101: Build Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/build-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 18:35:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/build-tools/</guid>
      <description>Build Tools: A Hasty Overview Front-end build tools allow us to transpile, bundle, and optimize assets in various ways.
Now, technically, webpack is a module bundler and doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite fit in with Gulp and Grunt, which are &amp;ldquo;task runners,&amp;rdquo; but since there is great overlap in the functionality offered by each tool, I&amp;rsquo;ll just refer to them all collectively as &amp;ldquo;build tools.&amp;rdquo;
Grunt came first - let&amp;rsquo;s start with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Persistence</title>
      <link>/posts/persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 18:03:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/persistence/</guid>
      <description>June 1st, 2015, 6pm I pause the Javascript tutorial I&amp;rsquo;m watching, then I close the tab. ES6 can wait until tomorrow - it&amp;rsquo;s just a hobby anyway.
I glance at the thirty-something Chrome tabs I have open and just now notice the whirring fan, the heat emanating off the keyboard. I click OneTab to save them all and watch as they disappear, one-by-one, as fast as Chrome&amp;rsquo;s speedy little brain can manage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>string parsing &amp; data extraction</title>
      <link>/posts/developer-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 18:04:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/developer-site/</guid>
      <description>Summary My latest project at Nulab was to migrate over the old Developer Website (containing API documentation, mostly) from Drupal to something new. The old site had become somewhat clumsy to manage, and we needed a new solution.
After initially considering WordPress, we ultimately landed on Hugo, a static site generator (SSG) written in Go. An SSG was perfect for our use-case. But migrating the data was non-trivial. But first things first&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling 101: Package Managers</title>
      <link>/posts/package-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 18:42:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/package-managers/</guid>
      <description>Zoom back to 2012. I&amp;rsquo;m in my dorm room trying to learn Ruby on Rails. Everything is going smoothly! Rails seems magical - perhaps a bit too much. I try to add a feature or two, and my progress comes to a screeching halt. I&amp;rsquo;m chasing down errors in the terminal with no conception of what&amp;rsquo;s going on.
 What the hell is a &amp;ldquo;gem&amp;rdquo;?!?!?
 And thus, I was introduced to the world of Package Managers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling 101: Introduction</title>
      <link>/posts/tooling-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 21:36:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tooling-101/</guid>
      <description>While the barriers to web development are substantially lower than many other fields, there&amp;rsquo;s still a bunch of junk that makes it frustrating for beginners to jump in.
By &amp;ldquo;obstacles,&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t mean the inherent difficulty in learning a new field, nor the complexity of advanced web development topics. I&amp;rsquo;m referring to the snags that slow progress without benefit.
For example, consider the act of going for a jog. Running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adelie Developer&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>/projects/adg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/adg/</guid>
      <description>🚨 A Note  This group has long ago stopped being a resource for newer developers to share tips and support; it is now just a group of colleagues staying in touch. 😄  Beer me, Slackbot! 🍺 The Adelie Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group was an online, Slack-based study group for web development.
The group is beginner-friendly and project-oriented. Currently, some of the members are working on individual developer portfolio websites using modern front-end tooling and best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backlog CLI</title>
      <link>/projects/blg-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/blg-cli/</guid>
      <description>Backlog CLI An (unofficial) command line utility for working with Backlog, a tool by Nulab, Inc.
 View on Github  Values  Be easy to &amp;ldquo;plug and play.&amp;rdquo; Provide shortcuts for a subset of your most frequently repeated actions, rather than achieving complete feature parity. In other words, it is designed to be a complement to Backlog, rather than a replacement for it.  Main Features  Quickly create, view, and open pull requests in the browser for your current branch &amp;amp; issue  blg pr create [-b BRANCH_TO_MERGE_TO] blg pr ls blg pr open   View and open your latest notifications  blg n   Quickly access misc links  blg me to list links related to your user account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Is Not That Hard</title>
      <link>/posts/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/coding/</guid>
      <description>Within the past two years, about a dozen people told me they’re extremely interested in learning how to code. Today, none of them are programmers, developers, or even hobby coders. Most of them, as far as I know, have never even opened a text editor.
The conversation always goes the same way. They want to learn, they have ideas, but it’s all too hard. One of my more determined friends — an art major — admired the idea of focusing on a single project all day, but he would routinely shudder at the sight of actual code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Design Is Not Subjective.</title>
      <link>/posts/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/design/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects. There are times when the difference between two choices is completely lateral — two substitutable alternatives that are equal in importance and consequence. If you’re craving some fruit, it doesn’t matter whether you choose the apple or the orange. In these instances, it’s okay to defer to preference, precedent, or a coin toss. But these cases are the (rare) exception, not the rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys</title>
      <link>/projects/keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/keys/</guid>
      <description>Keys: A work-in-progress  Explore and create shareable mechanical keyboard builds using the configurator tool. Get recommendations based on your preferences and use-case  Roadmap  Explore deals Coordinate group-buys  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milton Bros</title>
      <link>/projects/milton-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/milton-bros/</guid>
      <description>Milton &amp;amp; Candle The &amp;ldquo;Milton Bros&amp;rdquo; project was my first soiree into the world of character design. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had ambitions to develop a game - I think it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate form of expression - and while I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat comfortable in learning the development side of things, creating game art was always an extremely foreign world.
I designed Milton (pictured) and &amp;ldquo;Candle&amp;rdquo;, among several other bizarre characters, as a way to dive right into experimenting with simple shapes to build memorable characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosu</title>
      <link>/projects/mosu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mosu/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn, Hired, Vettery, Indeed, Monster&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;🙅‍♀️ Mosu (NOW RETIRED) arose out of my personal frustration with the process of job hunting. There are something like a dozen different &amp;ldquo;job board&amp;rdquo; websites, each with their own quirks. I found myself running around between ten different accounts, trying to remember which job applications were in which &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;:
 Saved, or &amp;ldquo;To Be Applied To&amp;rdquo; Application sent Currently interviewing Successfully received an offer  The experience was complete 💩 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Messenger</title>
      <link>/projects/nightmessenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nightmessenger/</guid>
      <description>Ow, my eyes 👀 Messenger.com is a relatively little-known messaging interface for Facebook Messenger. It&amp;rsquo;s a great (and less power-hungry) alternative to the little chat window you get as part of the standard Facebook desktop experience.
I&amp;rsquo;d often work late in the night, and found that using Messenger.com would hurt my eyes. I had somewhat recently discovered the world of Chrome extension development, so I decided to dive in and see if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a darker theme for Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small beginnings</title>
      <link>/scrawls/small-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scrawls/small-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Savor the winter bite,
Though it stiffens your fingers to uselessness,
Though as shards of glass, it moves to
Pierce and flay you bare to bone
Just to remind you again
That you are not welcome here
Savor it regardless; for it will
Recommend you in the end, and testify on your behalf:
He was cold so they could be warm
Savor the exile,
As their aspersions echo in triplicate,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Day 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/techday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/techday/</guid>
      <description>Today, I got the awesome opportunity to represent one of Nulab&amp;rsquo;s apps, Typetalk.
I donned my Nulab tee and hoodie, strapped on the goldenrod &amp;ldquo;Tech Day Exhibitor&amp;rdquo; bracelet, and walked into the sprawling space. At first, I saw the big names - AWS, American Airlines, Vimeo. I continued to the rear end of the space, where we had a table. Japanese candies, t-shirts &amp;amp; totes, business cards, iPads, Macbook Pros with our apps on full-screen - we&amp;rsquo;re ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Blindly Loving Your Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tools/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects. I once heard two friends arguing. One of them had recently come upon a windfall of cash, and wanted to make a big purchase: an upscale sports car. Upon hearing this, his miserly friend fired back, “you don’t even go places! Don’t buy a Porsche to drive to 711.”
When I heard this biting exchange, I chuckled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websites Are Like Pants</title>
      <link>/posts/websites-are-pants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/websites-are-pants/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects. In 2005, psychologist Barry Schwartz took the stage at TEDGlobal in Oxford and proposed an idea: that “more is less.” You can watch the full video here, but the core idea is simple. To quote Schwartz, “With so many options to choose from, people find it very difficult to choose at all.” He tells a simple anecdote to that effect: many years ago, when he walked into a clothing store, there were only a few pairs of jeans to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
