<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Oh | Web Developer on </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kevin Oh | Web Developer on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 12:54:35 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Futility</title>
      <link>/posts/on-futility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 12:54:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-futility/</guid>
      <description>An elderly woman wakes up at 7AM on a brisk Saturday morning. She picks up a bucket of white paint - an impulse buy from a week prior at a local Sherwin-Williams. Grabbing a brush and a tattered rag, she walks to the backyard.
She lives in the lower level of a duplex, so the backyard is hers. Lining the perimeter is an old fence - rusty streaks snake downward from every unsealed joint and the sight casts a macabre pallor over the space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Skills - Compromising</title>
      <link>/posts/on-compromise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 17:00:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-compromise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An indiscriminately stubborn engineer is a ceiling for their team&amp;rsquo;s potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation with Shortcuts on iOS</title>
      <link>/posts/ios-shortcuts-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 17:00:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ios-shortcuts-automation/</guid>
      <description>Shortcuts lets you automate stuff easily. I used it to build a COVID-19 health screening check in automation with Raspberry Pi back-end running Puppeteer. Fun stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toddlers in Porsches with Plasma Weapons</title>
      <link>/posts/toddlers-in-porsches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 17:00:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/toddlers-in-porsches/</guid>
      <description>In this one TED talk, Malcolm Gladwell told a story about how the U.S. military once spent $3 billion dollars developing a &amp;ldquo;scope&amp;rdquo; (as in, a telescopic sight for a weapon) for planes to attack their targets with terrifying accuracy. When it worked, it was considered revolutionary. The so-called Norden Bombsight made it possible to &amp;ldquo;drop bombs into a pickle barrel from 20,000 feet.&amp;rdquo; God-like accuracy for the time.
However - Gladwell later laments that regardless of the US Military&amp;rsquo;s newfound technical capability, it led to little actual progress because:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Workflow Tips</title>
      <link>/posts/workflow-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:28:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/workflow-tips/</guid>
      <description>The list of workflow tips I wish I had when I started. Indefinitely a WIP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Persistence</title>
      <link>/posts/persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 18:03:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/persistence/</guid>
      <description>I pause the Javascript tutorial I&amp;rsquo;m watching, then I close the tab. ES6 can wait until tomorrow - it&amp;rsquo;s just a hobby anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>string parsing &amp; data extraction</title>
      <link>/posts/developer-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 18:04:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/developer-site/</guid>
      <description>A recent project required converting a many-thousand-line document written in a proprietary syntax to Markdown. This is a peek at the messiness that ensued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Coding Is Too Hard&#34;</title>
      <link>/posts/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/coding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the past two years, about a dozen people told me they’re extremely interested in learning how to code. Today, &lt;em&gt;none&lt;/em&gt; of them are programmers, developers, or even hobby coders. Most of them, as far as I know, have never even opened a text editor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adelie Developer&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>/projects/adg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/adg/</guid>
      <description>🚨 A Note  This group has long ago stopped being a resource for newer developers to share tips and support; it is now just a group of colleagues staying in touch. 😄  Beer me, Slackbot! 🍺 The Adelie Developer&amp;rsquo;s Group was an online, Slack-based study group for web development.
The group is beginner-friendly and project-oriented. Currently, some of the members are working on individual developer portfolio websites using modern front-end tooling and best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backlog CLI</title>
      <link>/projects/blg-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/blg-cli/</guid>
      <description>Backlog CLI An (unofficial) command line utility for working with Backlog, a tool by Nulab, Inc.
 View on Github  Values  Be easy to &amp;ldquo;plug and play.&amp;rdquo; Provide shortcuts for a subset of your most frequently repeated actions, rather than achieving complete feature parity. In other words, it is designed to be a complement to Backlog, rather than a replacement for it.  Main Features  Quickly create, view, and open pull requests in the browser for your current branch &amp;amp; issue  blg pr create [-b BRANCH_TO_MERGE_TO] blg pr ls blg pr open   View and open your latest notifications  blg n   Quickly access misc links  blg me to list links related to your user account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Design Is Not Subjective.</title>
      <link>/posts/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/design/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects. There are times when the difference between two choices is completely lateral — two substitutable alternatives that are equal in importance and consequence. If you’re craving some fruit, it doesn’t matter whether you choose the apple or the orange. In these instances, it’s okay to defer to preference, precedent, or a coin toss. But these cases are the (rare) exception, not the rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys</title>
      <link>/projects/keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/keys/</guid>
      <description>Keys: A work-in-progress  Explore and create shareable mechanical keyboard builds using the configurator tool. Get recommendations based on your preferences and use-case  Roadmap  Explore deals Coordinate group-buys  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milton Bros</title>
      <link>/projects/milton-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/milton-bros/</guid>
      <description>Milton &amp;amp; Candle The &amp;ldquo;Milton Bros&amp;rdquo; project was my first soiree into the world of character design. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had ambitions to develop a game - I think it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate form of expression - and while I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat comfortable in learning the development side of things, creating game art was always an extremely foreign world.
I designed Milton (pictured) and &amp;ldquo;Candle&amp;rdquo;, among several other bizarre characters, as a way to dive right into experimenting with simple shapes to build memorable characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosu</title>
      <link>/projects/mosu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mosu/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn, Hired, Vettery, Indeed, Monster&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;🙅‍♀️ Mosu (NOW RETIRED) arose out of my personal frustration with the process of job hunting. There are something like a dozen different &amp;ldquo;job board&amp;rdquo; websites, each with their own quirks. I found myself running around between ten different accounts, trying to remember which job applications were in which &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;:
 Saved, or &amp;ldquo;To Be Applied To&amp;rdquo; Application sent Currently interviewing Successfully received an offer  The experience was complete 💩 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Messenger</title>
      <link>/projects/nightmessenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nightmessenger/</guid>
      <description>Ow, my eyes 👀 Messenger.com is a relatively little-known messaging interface for Facebook Messenger. It&amp;rsquo;s a great (and less power-hungry) alternative to the little chat window you get as part of the standard Facebook desktop experience.
I&amp;rsquo;d often work late in the night, and found that using Messenger.com would hurt my eyes. I had somewhat recently discovered the world of Chrome extension development, so I decided to dive in and see if I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a darker theme for Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small beginnings</title>
      <link>/scrawls/small-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scrawls/small-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Savor the winter bite,
Though it stiffens your fingers to uselessness,
Though as shards of glass, it moves to
Pierce and flay you bare to bone
Just to remind you again
That you are not welcome here
Savor it regardless; for it will
Recommend you in the end, and testify on your behalf:
He was cold so they could be warm
Savor the exile,
As their aspersions echo in triplicate,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Day 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/techday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/techday/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended Tech Day 2017. (&amp;hellip;) Soon, I ditched the elevator pitch I had prepared almost immediately and just simply began to have earnest conversations with them about their current tools and processes. It was awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Blindly Loving Your Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tools/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects. I once heard two friends arguing. One of them had recently come upon a windfall of cash, and wanted to make a big purchase: an upscale sports car. Upon hearing this, his miserly friend fired back, “you don’t even go places! Don’t buy a Porsche to drive to 711.”
When I heard this biting exchange, I chuckled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websites Are Like Pants</title>
      <link>/posts/websites-are-pants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/websites-are-pants/</guid>
      <description>This post was written back when Adelie was openly accepting new inquiries and projects. In 2005, psychologist Barry Schwartz took the stage at TEDGlobal in Oxford and proposed an idea: that “more is less.” You can watch the full video here, but the core idea is simple. To quote Schwartz, “With so many options to choose from, people find it very difficult to choose at all.” He tells a simple anecdote to that effect: many years ago, when he walked into a clothing store, there were only a few pairs of jeans to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
